Francis Yang

Tech and business savvy, proactive, detail oriented and responsible. Software Engineer (2017 New Graduate) who dedicates to building services and applications that promote ultimate performance and user experience. izayacity@gmail.com +1(669)264-9019 Santa Clara, CA, US https://izayacity.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

TO-ON KIKAKU CO.,LTD

11/2015 - 02/2016

Web Develop Intern

Tokyo, Japan

- Contributed developing <u>lesson-time.com</u> and its mobile app, a piano education system.
- Assisted non-tech coworkers to monitor the server by developing a backend middleware independently.
- Created charts of server usage and optimized 1000+ SQL and GQL reading from 40s to less than 1s.
- (GAE | Datastore | Memcache | PHP | MySQL | Slim | JavaScript | Ionic | Bootstrap | AJAX | REST APIs | Go)

NSFOCUS INC. 11/2014 – 04/2015

Test and Develop Intern

Beijing, China

- Systematized device reservation process by developing a lab management system using Python Django.
- Created scripts that made auto-analysis in stead of previous manually checking 7000+ rules for 2 weeks.
- Contributed IPS hardware test at data center and worked between 4 departments.
- (Python | Django | jQuery | Regex | C++ | Snort | Linux | VM | Protocols | Excel | Bugzilla | UML | SSH | Cisco)

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SANTA CRUZ

09/2016 - 09/2017

M.Sc. in Games and Playable Media of Computational Media

BEIJING UNIVERSITY OF POSTS AND TELECOMMUNICATIONS

09/2011 - 07/2015

B.Eng. in Network Engineering of Computer Science

Beijing, China

California, USA

PROJECTS

Online Card Game (HearthStone-style, solo without support)

06/2017 - 08/2017

- Architected the tech stack and made weekly plans, reports, scrum (using Trello) and code reviews.
- Created <u>JSON-RPC APIs on GitLab</u> and a jQuery networking test tool that enabled continuous development in stead of re-building 2 clients locally.
- Handled threading, runtime instantiation, coroutine challenges and deployed the server onto Docker container and AWS ECS.
- (NodeJS | ExpressJS | Unity C# | Socket.IO | ¡Query | Docker container | AWS)

Tornado Tower Game (VR Platformer on Oculus, exhibited on E3 2017)

01/2017 - 06/2017

- Lead Programmer of Dizzy Slugs, a team of 10+ people.
- Developed gameplay such as traps, enemies, file data system, audio... using Unreal Engine 4.
- Managed the team to use Git tools, ensured branch merging correctly and maintained AWS Route53.
- Impacted team decisions and optimized processes resulting in the team's progress ahead of competitors.

SKILLS

TECH: C++ | JavaScript | C# | PHP | Golang | Java | Python | NodeJS | Ionic | RESTful APIs | GraphQL | Socket | Unity | Unreal Engine 4 | AWS | Google App Engine | SQL | NoSQL | Linux | Docker | Agile

LANGUAGES: English: Fluent | Chinese: Fluent | Japanese: Intermediate (with JLPT N3 Certificate)

INTERESTS: Tech | Business | Gaming | Anime | Soccer | Foreign Culture | Social Events | Outdoor